okay this is Richard with hydrogen
technology today.com in the video just
before this I showed you this cell uh 17
plate design running on pure tap water
it's pulling about 5
amps uh producing around 5 to six um a
minute not very much really um you know
not really ideal um what I do want to do
though
is put in a little sodium hydroxide here
which is the crystal drain opener from
Lowe's um ideally when you do this you
measure it out you mix it with a little
water and uh we're going to do that now
you got a basically a
quarter a quarter of a teaspoon here and
I'm only going to put in about half that
not very much which really comes out to
be around an eigh of a
teaspoon
so put that in our little sandless Sil
Cup going to grab us a bottle of
water uh you want to mix this up
first you know get it get it good and
diluted before you add it into your into
your
cell uh mix this up
kind of watch the bubbles here this
is about uh 60 oz
of pure water out of a tap we're on a
well out here and I do have a Culligan
system so there's some there's some
enrichment being done to the water but
uh you know here's the cell 17 plates
there's the uh amperage I'm just going
to turn off my my charger here real
quick and open this
up uh
just mix in this sodium
hydroxide pre miixed you don't want to
touch this
stuff that's not a real good
idea mix it stir
it I'm trying to be a cameraman and a
wacko scientist wnab be so here we
go all right it's going to take the cell
in and out just make sure that each
individual plate gets get some liquid in
between it so we get a good good
test okay closing it back
up there two back remember this is an
eighth of a teaspoon of sodium
hydroxide so here we go watch the
cell quite a bit more
hydrogen pull
in about 10 amps now also take in
consideration that this cell has not
been what's called conditioned um here's
the results of the bubbles quite a bit
more coming out
and as the water becomes more
active uh and the sodium hydroxide gets
a little more mixed into this tap water
we'll pull just a few more amps and
ultimately this particular
setup uh will will produce around a
liter a minute uh below 15 amps if I add
a little more sodium hydroxide I pull
more amperage the water heats up a
little more and uh I produce more
hydrogen
there's good and bad things about that
some Vehicles don't need that much
hydrogen this particular setup will
produce around a liter a minute um with
just an eighth of a teaspoon of sodium
hydroxide in tap water